#### Curriculum

# Renato Ferreira

Bralizian, 29

Address: Schiedam, netherlands

**Email**: renatoferreira.dev@gmail.com **Github**: https://github.com/RenatoRJF

Phone: +31 062 532 02 46

### **ABOUT ME**

As an experienced software engineer I have already worked for just over 7 years. Although for most of my career I have been focused on application development by taking on the role of front-end developer, my skills also extend to backend and mobile development. I have already worked and tried several languages and technologies, but today, the main focus is on building applications (web, mobile, server) with Javascript technologies. Among several frameworks and libraries, my preference is the stack with React, React Native and NodeJS. Two things that describe me as a professional are: learning new things and sharing knowledge.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

#### VONQ

Frontend Engineer - July 2019 - Current Job

VONQ is a company based in Rotterdam whose product is a platform that helps recruiters to create campaigns for jobs in a centralized way and buy channels integrated to publish job opportunities. My main responsibilities are: To maintain the Job Market Platform which was created with React + Redux by adding new functionalities, integrating new technologies and aligning the user experience with the Marketing department. Our backend is implemented with PHP and Symphony framework. The main technologies we use are: **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **ES6+**,**Jest**, **PHP**, **Symphony**. We are an agile team and we use the **SCRUM** Methodology for it.

# **Thales Group**

Senior Frontend developer - April 2018 to July 2019

Thales group is a multinational company whose main products are systems related to security, military and transportation. As front-end developer at the Thales Group Portugal, I was responsible for creating core components based on the Javascript and Web Components concept. The goal of building these web Components was to share functional modules of software to other developers of Thales around the world and help them to maintain the consistency between different applications. I was also responsible for leading a small team of junior developers. The main technologies I used in this experience were: **Polymer, Typescript, ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJs, Selenium**. We were also using **SCRUM** as agile methodology and **TDD** programming practice.

# **SpotQA**

Frontend Engineer - July 2017 - March 2018

SpotQA is a startup based in London whose main products are related to quality assurance. In the period that I was working there as Frontend engineer, my main responsibilities were: to maintain the website that was made with wordpress, maintain reactjs projects and implement one of the main applications by using VueJS + VueX. The main technologies I used in this experience were: HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS + Redux, VueJS + VueX, D3.js, Wordpress. We were also using SCRUM as agile methodology and TDD programming practice.

#### Alocado

Teach Lead Frontend Engineer - November 2016 to June 2017

Alocado was a startup based in São Paulo whose product was an application for renting places (e.g. offices) for hours. As a front-end developer I was responsible for creating and maintaining the platform by using the following technologies: **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **VueJS**, **VueX**, **Jest**, **ES6**. The backend was implemented with **PHP** and **LaraveI**. We were also using **SCRUM** as agile methodology and **TDD** programming practice.

#### Planedia

Frontend Developer - October 2015 - November 2016

Planedia was a startup based in Portugal whose product was an application for planning trips. As Frontend developer, my main responsibilities were to migrate the application from AngularJS to React + Redux. The main technologies I used in this experience were: **AngularJS**, **React +** 

**Redux**, **HTML**, **CSS3**, **Karma**, **Jasmine**, **Chai**. We were using **SCRUM** as agile methodology and **TDD** programming practice.

# **Legislative Assembly**

Fullstack developer - June 2013 - September 2015

As full-stack developer, I was responsible for building and maintaining an internal system for the government of the state of Pernambuco, Brazil. The main technologies used to build this software were: **C#**, **SQLServer**, **AngularJS**, **HTML5** and **CSS3**. We were using **SCRUM** as agile methodology and **TDD** programming practice.

## OTHER PROJECTS

# Laudite

Javascript Full-stack developer - From Fev 2020

Laudite is a project related to the creation of medical reports using the speech recognition API from google and artificial intelligence. The project consists of accelerating the generation of medical reports in the radiology sector. My main responsibilities in this project consist of creating new features, migrating legacy code, checking the codes of other freelancers, etc. The main technologies used in this project are: Vue, Vuex, Vuetify, NodeJS, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, HTML5, CSS3, jest, ES6 +, etc.: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Vue,, NodeJS, Elasticsearch, MongoDB.

#### **EventCheck**

Javascript Full-stack developer - Dec 2019 - Fev 2020

EventCheck is an app to help people to create, manage and collaborate with all kinds of events. My main responsibilities were to implement the entire app by using **React**Native, styled-components and also create and maintain the API with NodeJS.

#### Jimbo

Frontend Developer - April 2015 to June 2017

Jimbo was a startup whose product was a system to automate the job interview process. There I was responsible for implementing new features and creating components with the following technologies: **React**, **Redux**, **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **Jest**. We also implemented the backend using **PHP** by using the Laravel framework. We were using **SCRUM** as agile methodology and **TDD** programming practice.

### **MGPLAN**

Full-stack developer - April 2016 to June 2017

MGPlan was an agency based in Recife, Brazil. As a freelancer, I was responsible for creating sites, landing pages and small systems. The main technologies I had an opportunity to use were: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, JQuery, php, Laravel, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Analysis and development of systems**

UNIBRATEC, Recife (Brazil) - 2013 – 2016
PERSONAL SKILLS

# Programming/Markup/Stylesheet/Notation languages

Javascript [ES5, ES6, ES7, ES8] (Browser and Node.js), TypeScript, PHP, CSS3, JSON, HTML5, JSX, C#

# **Preprocessors/Static type checkers**

SASS, Compass, LESS, PostCSS

# **Back-end - PHP frameworks**

Laravel, Symphony

# **Back-end - Node.js frameworks & libraries**

Express, Socket.IO, Swagger for Node.js, AdonisJs, Next.js, Gatsby, Pug

#### Front-end- Frameworks & Libraries

React, Redux, Vue.js, Vuex, jQuery, Axios, Lodash, Bootstrap, Material-Ul, Angular, Styled components

# **Mobile - Frameworks & Libraries**

React Native

# **Linting/Code Quality Tool**

Eslint, JSLint, Standard JS, PHP\_CodeSniffer

# **Query languages**

SQL, MongoDB Queries, GraphQL

#### **Databases**

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, SQLite, SQLServer

# **Prototyping**

Sketch, Adobe XD, Zeplin

#### **Version control**

GIT

# **Test tools**

Jest, Enzyme, Jasmine, Selenium, cypress

# **REST API description tool**

Swagger

#### CMS

WordPress

# **Dependency managers**

Composer, Yarn, Npm, Bower

# Module bundlers & Task runners

Webpack, Gulp

# **Work/Deployment environment**

Docker, Heroku, Linode, Generic shared hosts

#### Others skills

Babel, Storybook, REST, MVC, ORM, OOP, Functional programming, SOLID, Scrum, Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, Progressive web apps, Reactive programming, Responsive design, Web standards, Performance, Usability, Accessibility, SEO